# **Ross Qualey**

701.306.8278 ♦ Fargo, ND 58102 ♦ qualeyro@gmail.com ♦ linkedin.com/in/rossqualey

Extremely dependable, competitive, and achievement-oriented Sales Representative with passion for technology and head for successful business leadership, operations, and improvements. Customer-facing sales experience. Work independently with solid time management skills; support other performing team members. Communicate effectively with all levels of internal and external decision makers.

- ♦ Strategic Sales and Customer Relationships: Driven to develop and manage profitable relationships with internal and external customers. Leverage relationships to expand revenue, number of locations, product types, and staff quality and quantity.
- ♦ Technology: Learn technical products quickly. Adept in Microsoft Technologies including Windows 10, Office 365, Outlook, PowerPoint, Word, Excel, OneNote, and others including Skype. Learning Azure on Lynda.com. Use Cloud Services / Cloud Computing for file storage, collaborative tools, and SaaS.

# Recommendation

"Ross is an excellent leader with a strong ethical and moral compass. He sets high expectations for himself and expects nothing less from those with whom he works. He is a masterful "reader" of people. I have witnessed his constant situational monitoring and excellent interpersonal skills dealing with multiple business leaders of differing personalities. Ross is efficient, organized, and detailed oriented, all skills required to sell and maintain services our organization provides."

Don Santer, MBA, Chief Executive Officer, NDAD

# **Experience**

# North Dakota Association for the Disabled, Fargo, ND

May 2000 to Present

Charitable nonprofit assisting people with disabilities in North Dakota, many ineligible for services from other agencies.

**Gaming Director,** January 2009 to Present

Plan, develop, operate, and supervise gaming activity at 5 sites in Fargo and West Fargo, ND. Hire, train, motivate, and supervise 3 managers. Oversee largest number of sites and employees in entire organization.

- ♦ Sales and Customer Relationships: Build positive and profitable relationships, serving as point of contact with customers, business owners, business managers, staff, Attorney General's Office, Simulcast Service Provider, distributors, and general public. Leveraged relationships, marketing and sales expertise to increase annual revenue in Fargo 100%+, from \$850,000 in 2009 to \$3.46 million in 2016, by opening 4 new locations, adding product types, and expanding hours of operation.
- ♦ Opportunity Management: Took on director responsibilities with 1 site. Using entrepreneurial strategy, added product within 6 weeks through presentation regarding rental income for business owner during time when most organizations were abandoning this product.

- Marketing and Sales Techniques: Designed marketing billboards and promotional TV advertising.
  Delivered sales presentations to business owners and managers to initiate long-term relationships.
- ♦ **Staff Development:** Increased staff in Fargo 100%. Positioned organization as most talented staff in Fargo by networking with frontline employees in other organizations and hiring away best workers.
- ♦ Partnerships: Increase business for host locations by hiring well-known, talented staff who bring customers with them, attract new customers, and increase customer length of stay with game skill, conversational ability, and relationship building. Business owners appreciate reliable, friendly staff.
- ♦ Staff Relationship Management: Mitigated crises by overseeing difficult management transitions in Bismarck and Grand Forks, ND, locations. Turned around "hatchet man" image and prevented employee turnover through collaborative, transparent, and fair relationships. Dropped turnover to lowest level in statewide organization.
- Portfolio Management: Consistently met or exceeded annual sales goals by developing and nurturing collaboration with business owners and managers, recognizing and responding to opportunities. Improved organization reputation to current impeccable level, receiving recommendations and inquiries from business owners and managers.
- ♦ **Forecasting:** Recognize and respond to trends, including technology. Led experiment with handheld electronic bingo game, for example.
- ◆ **Technologies:** Tested and rejected electronic document viewing system for 1 gaming site and Fargo office, 2016. Currently testing editable PDFs as alternative.
- ♦ **Program Development:** Create and evaluate programs and projects, including site opening and closing strategies to increase customer engagement and volume.
- ♦ **Communications:** Equally comfortable with all levels of customers, partners, and staff, from lobbying State Senators and Representatives to training new employee to shuffle cards.
- ◆ **Recognition:** Promotion from blackjack dealer to site manager motivated by thorough knowledge of operations and consistent initiative, 2009. Promoted to gaming director for 3 cities, 2009; Fargo Director, 2014.

# Tri-State Financial Services, Inc., Fargo, ND

January to December 2006

Provided financial solutions to residents of North Dakota, Minnesota, and Wisconsin.

#### **Loan Officer**

♦ **Sales:** Cold called prospects from county loan lists; consulted with them to refinance for better rate.

# Kirby Vacuum Cleaners, Fargo, ND

May 1996 to June 1997

Leading home cleaning company utilizing direct sales.

# **Outside Sales Representative**

♦ **Sales:** Learned to sell by consulting with customers, demonstrating value, and answering objections to find another door when one closed.

# **Education**

**MBA**, Concentration in Human Resource Management, University of Mary, Fargo, ND, 2015. **Bachelor of Science**, Graphic Communication, Minnesota State University, Moorhead, MN, 2006. **Continuing Education:** Fluenz French Course, 2017